<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Transverse</string>
    <string name="page_encyclopedia">Encyclopedia</string>
    <string name="page_add_new">Add New Entry</string>
    <string name="page_statistics">Statistics</string>
    <string name="page_self_help">Self-Help</string>
    <string name="page_settings">Settings</string>

    <!-- ADD NEW ENTRY FRAGMENT -->
    <string name="ane_mood_header">How are you feeling?</string>
    <string name="ane_tags_header">Tags</string>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">UwU</string>

    <!--SELF HELP ENTRIES-->
    <string name="SHWalk">
        Taking a walk, whether or not for exercise purposes, is useful for clearing your head and getting grounded. When we experience dysphoria, it is so easy to become fixated on certain aspects of your body that you can’t change, to the point where we don’t see anything outside that. Even a short walk around the block can break you out of that loop and remind you that there is beauty in life, and that dysphoria won’t be forever.
    </string>

    <string name="SHMeditate">
        <![CDATA[When we <strong>meditate</strong>, we learn to accept ourselves and where we are without judgment. When we are dealing with dysphoria, this may be hard because we want it to go away. Know that meditation isn’t about saying that dysphoria is okay, but rather that being aware of it without judgment makes it more manageable.
<h6></h6>
Do you want to learn how to meditate? Check out meditation apps such as Atom, Medito, and Headspace.
<h6></h6>
<strong>Grounding</strong> is also a way to stay in the moment. It is a practice of bringing yourself down from an uncomfortable emotional state. Strong sensory inputs can help you center yourself and feel more connected to your body.
Some examples include:
<ul>
<li>Chewing bitter coffee beans or tart raspberries and focusing on the flavor and sensation</li>
<li>Standing and taking a deep breath, focusing on how the solid ground feels under you </li>
<li>Making yourself aware of your surroundings by counting items in the room of one color or shape</li>
</ul>
]]>
    </string>

    <string name="SHSnuggle">
        <![CDATA[Science has proven that snuggling with your pets is a mood booster - but you didn’t need to know that to experience the comfort and calm that comes along with it. If you don’t have a furry critter of your own, a friend might have one you can visit. Local humane societies often have programs where you can volunteer to walk or play with pets. ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="SHExercise">
        <![CDATA[Exercise provides us with natural endorphins that boost our moods. It is also a distraction from feeling dysphoria. Even though it may not feel this way at the moment, your body is a good body. Exercise allows us to appreciate our bodies for things that they can do, and appreciate the efforts that our bodies give in helping us stay alive every single day.
<h6></h6>
If you don’t know what kinds of movements feel good to you, experiment! Some people enjoy jogging and weight lifting, while for others swimming, biking, and hiking may be more enjoyable. And you don’t have to exercise alone! Going with a buddy or two is not only fun but also gives you a chance to get closer.
<h6></h6>
However, for many people, exercise can worsen their eating disorders or body image, so if you fall under this category, we suggest doing another self-help method instead!
]]>
    </string>

    <string name="SHRead">
        <![CDATA[Reading is a great way to distract yourself from bad feelings. Grab an engaging book that you enjoy and focus on that for a while.]]>
    </string>

    <string name="SHMusic">
        <![CDATA[Having playlist of music for bad dysphoria days can help you get through them. Music is powerful especially when it’s hard to put words to your feelings. If you know of some artists or bands that help you feel better, it’s worth it to make a playlist of your favorite songs for times when you’re feeling especially down.]]>
    </string>

    <string name="SHTalk">
        <![CDATA[Do you have a friend you can talk to? Don’t underestimate the power of a listening ear! Talking about your feelings can help you better understand them, and help you feel like you’re not alone.
<h6></h6>
Other times it might help not to focus on the feelings but instead chat about other things. Distraction can help bring us down from a peak of emotion, and allow us perspective to feel better and manage our thoughts once the worst has passed.
<h6></h6>
Please feel free to also message us on Tumblr or Instagram if you want to talk. We are here for you. Check out these resources as well for finding an online community or friends to talk to!
]]>
    </string>

    <string name="SHHobby">
        <![CDATA[Often when we’re stuck with feelings of dysphoria, things can feel hopeless and we can feel powerless. Working on a hobby is a great way to feel like you’re in control of your surroundings and of yourself. Whether that’s practicing an instrument, writing, drawing, or crafting, you are creating something that’s important to you. It’s a gift to be able to create something, even if it’s just for yourself to enjoy.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="SHPray">
        <![CDATA[If you believe in a higher power, prayer can be a really beneficial way to relieve dysphoria. It has many benefits and can help ground you and clear your mind. Know that you are loved and that this won’t be forever.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="SHClothing">
        <![CDATA[“Comfort clothing” can mean different things to different people. For some, comfort clothing may be a big and comfortable hoodie. For others, comfort clothing may be clothes that give you a feeling of gender euphoria. When we’re feeling dysphoria, clothes can often be such a big part of that, and clothes that feel good can be a great help.]]>
    </string>

    <string name="SHBath">
       <![CDATA[<Depending on the type of dysphoria you’re feeling, taking a bath may help you feel better. It’s an especially form of self-care, because you’re worth it. To make your bath even nicer, use bath salts or a bath bomb, turn down the lights, light a few candles, and play some relaxing music.
<h6></h6>
Sometimes, you could benefit from a long bath or just a quick shower, but feel you will be distressed by seeing your body. To navigate this, try covering your bathroom mirror with a sheet or towel and bathing with the lights out. It can take some feeling around in the dark and moving a bit slower, but can be a relief for acute distress surrounding bathing time until you feel more comfortable.
]]>
    </string>


    <!--ENCYCLOPEDIA ENTRIES -->
    <string name="b01">
        <![CDATA[
        Gender is an identifier in the range of masculinity and femininity as dictated by social and cultural normatives.
<h6></h6>
That’s pretty wordy - let’s break it down a bit.
<h6></h6>
Most people are raised with the assumption that gender is tied to sex - associating being male with being born with a penis and testicles, and female as being born with a vagina and ovaries. However, gender is not tied to sex, and is not as simple as being male or female. Gender is a spectrum of identities, far beyond one type of man and one type of woman. Some people are born with attributes assigned male, but are actually female. Others might be born with attributes assigned female, but their gender is actually male. Some feel they are a man and woman in one, or somewhere in between, or neither. The gender binary is not between two neat categories, but can be thought of as a gradual scale from male/masculine to female/feminine, with androgyny in the middle.
<h6></h6>
Other people don’t fit on the scale at all, but fall outside of those cultural expectations and norms entirely. People who find themselves in between masculine and feminine, or outside of them, might consider themselves nonbinary.

]]>
    </string>
    <string name="b02">
        <![CDATA[
        Most people are raised being taught that gender and sexual characteristics are inherently tied together, when in fact, gender and sex are very different things.
<h6></h6>
First, let’s debunk some myths about sex. A person’s sex refers to their first (or “primary”) and secondary sexual characteristics. Primary sexual characteristics are present at birth - in humans, the usual example given is having a testes and penis or ovaries and a vagina. Secondary characteristics usually develop during puberty, like development of breast tissue, muscle, voice changes, facial hair, and body hair.
<h6></h6>
A lowered voice, facial and body hair, high muscle mass, XX chromosomes, and high testosterone levels are usually associated with being “masculine” and “male”.
<h6></h6>
A higher voice, sparse body hair, soft skin, breast development, XY chromosomes,  menstruation, and high estrogen levels are usually associated with being “feminine” and “female”.
<h6></h6>
However, even without including transgender people, hundreds of millions of people are born and develop traits differing from what is associated with their assigned sex. Women assigned female at birth can have little to no breast tissue, high testosterone levels, XX chromosomes, lower voices, thick body hair, facial hair, and high musculature. Men assigned male at birth can have breast tissue and lactation abilities, XY chromosomes, high estrogen, low testosterone, little to no body hair or facial hair, a higher voice, and low muscle mass.
<h6></h6>
Cis men and women can have any combination of these secondary characteristics, and people are born with infinite variations on appearance and function of their genitalia. Many people are born with primary and secondary sexual characteristics that do not fit easily into being defined as a penis, a vagina, testes, ovaries, or can have different combinations. People with these traits are considered “intersex”. Intersex people can also have different balances of hormones, that can effect secondary sexual characteristics like body hair and voice.
<h6></h6>
<em>More information on being intersex here:
<a href="https://www.hrc.org/resources/understanding-the-intersex-community">https://www.hrc.org/resources/understanding-the-intersex-community</a></em>
<h6></h6>
With all of these combinations and variations, there is not one singular trait that defines what makes a man a “biological” man, or a woman a “biological” woman. Someone can be born with a penis whose sexual characteristics are, in every other way, traits of a <strong>cisgender (non transgender)</strong> woman. A person can be born with XY chromosomes who, in every other way, present traits of a cisgender man. There are infinite variations and combinations of what traits a person can be born with or develop. None of these traits, combinations, or exceptions decide what gender you identify as.
<h6></h6>
Next, let’s debunk some ideas about what gender is. In almost any culture, there are ideas about what things are considered “feminine” and “masculine” - scents, clothes, colors, hobbies, interests, professions, everything. However, none of these things are worldwide or static in any way. In America, the color blue is linked with masculinity and the color pink with femininity. But these colors don’t have genders, they are just colors. Before WWII, the color blue was actually associated with femininity, and the color pink with masculinity. Nothing about the colors have changed since then except for their opinion in popular culture and society. There is no difference between a kilt and a skirt, yet one is associated with masculinity, and the other is usually associated with femininity. There are a million examples of meaningless “gendered” items, styles, and concepts - but none of them dictate gender identity.
<h6></h6>
Your gender identity is an innate sense of self as a man, woman, or other gender. It is not dependent on any sexuality, gender expression, or biological trait.

]]>
    </string>
    <string name="b03">
        <![CDATA[Some people start to suspect they are transgender because they feel uncomfortable identifying and/or presenting as their assigned gender, or because they feel good identifying and/or presenting as a different gender identity. You can experiment with this in makeup, clothing, safe chest binders, or breast forms and see how it makes you feel! Some common things for transgender people to do before they understand their identity: admiring and relating to characters that are men, women, or other gender identities and presentations. Maybe you are into cosplay, but all the characters you like to dress as are a different gender than your assigned one, and you feel euphoric when presenting that way. Perhaps whenever you play a game, you always gravitate towards playing a character different than your assigned gender, or a shapeshifter. These can be indicators that you might not be cis, but as with all things, it is not a rule. When you look at characters or people you admire, what do you admire about them? When you picture your ideal self, what does that ideal self look like? Are they androgynous? Feminine? Masculine? Fluid? These are not easy questions to answer, but can be helpful to think about.
<h6></h6>
When it comes down to it, the chances are if you are often questioning if you are transgender, then you likely are. This is not a rule, but it is fairly common - <strong>*cis</strong> people don’t usually continually question if they are actually trans.
<h6></h6>
Some people know from a very young age that they are of a transgender identity, while others don’t come to understand it until late in life. Everyone has their own path to forming and understanding their identity. While it can be frustrating for these concepts to not have easy answers, the good news is that there is no wrong way to be trans as long as you are on a path towards your happiest self! Your gender is YOUR journey, and no one can decide it for you. Above all, seek the YOU that is happiest with YOURSELF.
<h6></h6>
<strong>*Cis</strong> - A shorthand for Cisgender, meaning identifying with the gender assigned to you at birth.
]]>
    </string>
    <string name="b04">
        <![CDATA[It is incredibly common to feel you aren’t “enough” of something to be somehow properly able to take that title. That feeling does not discredit your gender identity at all. People often also struggle with this when they are genderfluid, genderqueer, nonbinary, or gender non-conforming, as these identities don’t “fit” into constant or binary boxes.
<h6></h6>
Chances are, if you keep questioning if you are transgender, then you probably are. The two most important things to keep in mind is that gender identities can grow and change, and that gender is a spectrum. Experimenting with different presentations*, names, and pronouns can help you get a feel for what makes you happiest!
<h6></h6>
Through some time and experimentation, you may find there is a way that makes you feel most authentically yourself. This may include being gender non-conforming, transgender, or both!
<h6></h6>
There is no downside to experimenting with and exploring your gender. If you find out you are transgender, then you have learned something about your identity, and can look at what you need to do to be happiest in your identity. Alternatively, you might discover you are not transgender, but you have had the oppurtunity to explore your gender, satisfy your curiousity, and hopefully come out the other side understanding the trans and GNC* people around you a little bit better. Thinking you might be transgender or identifying as transgender, and later feeling you are not, is not disrespectful, fake, or misleading. You deserve a safe space to explore your gender, no matter the outcome.
<h6></h6>
*Presenting different ways (dressing a way typically masculine, feminine, or androgynous)
<h6></h6>
*Gender Non-Conforming

]]>
    </string>

    <string name="c01">
        <![CDATA[Some people might start by sharing with a close friend or family member who they trust and might understand. Some people don’t come out to their family for a long time, or choose not to share with family at all. Some people introduce themselves at their works as being transgender, and others don’t feel an interest or need in sharing that part of themselves with anyone at their workplace. When you are considering what you want to and are ready to share with people in your life, always focus on the goal of what would make YOU happiest, and once you know what you want, you can work from there to achieve those goals. A trusted friend, family member, or mentor can help you decide if and how to discuss your identity with others.
<h6></h6>
Here on Transverse we have some pointers and tips for broaching the subject in different places in your life, and many others have shared their experiences online in online transgender and transgender-friendly resources. Therapists, especially ones specializing in gender identity counseling, can help you to navigate these conversations with teachers, classmates, coworkers, friends, and family. Again - above all, prioritize your own happiness and comfort, and work towards those most supportive realities.
<h6></h6>
In an ideal world, “coming out” as trans wouldn’t be a big deal, or better yet, would be treated as something to celebrate! Not everyone in our lives understands transgenderism though, and might not be supportive. Here are a few ways you might go about broaching the subject in a few different scenarios.
]]>
    </string>
    <string name="c02">
        <![CDATA[You don’t HAVE to do anything when it comes to your identity - it belongs to you and is no one’s business but your own. Sharing your gender identity with friends, family, and workplaces can feel very validating and for some can be the key of feeling welcome in all of your social spaces.
]]>
    </string>
    <string name="c03">
        <![CDATA[
        Writing a letter or email can sometimes be a good way to have down what you want to say, without being interrupted. It can give the recipient some time to consider their own response before they make it, instead of just having an initial reaction. This can be a great option if you feel difficulty talking about it, if you feel you might be interrupted, or if you feel the recipient might need some time to reply.
<h6> </h6>
Start the email with a personal note, about how you’ve been feeling, and how through introspection you have realized your gender identity as X. Some people will need transgenderism explained to them - there are many great resources online or on this app that could help explain it to them. Take a moment to find one that you feel explains it well and relates to your experience, and include a link, or write the important parts out if the recipient is not computer-savvy. It is common for people to have questions, and you might want to address some basic ones in the email to them. Many people don’t understand the difference between gender and sexuality, and they may ask about your sexual identity. If you are religious, they might ask you what this means to you in the context of your religion.They also may ask how you intend to transition. It’s okay to not be sure yet how you want to transition, but if there are steps you know you want to take like pronoun changes, name changes, HRT, or top surgery, you might include those as your plans.

]]>
    </string>
    <string name="c04">
        <![CDATA[
        Find a moment to talk to them without a lot of risk of interruption or distraction, and tell them there’s something you’ve been thinking about that you need to talk to them about, or that you’re ready to share with them. Start off speaking a little about how you’ve been feeling, what you’ve considered and how through introspection you have realized you don’t fit your gender assigned at birth. Some people will need transgenderism explained to them - there are many great resources online or on this app that could help explain it to them. Take a moment to find one that you feel explains it well and relates to your experience, and use it as a base to explain it to them in a way they might better understand.
<h6></h6>
 It is common for people to have questions. Many people don’t understand the difference between gender and sexuality, and they may ask about your sexual identity. If you are religious, they may ask you what this means in the context of your religion. They also may ask how you intend to transition. It’s okay to not be sure yet how you want to transition, but if there are steps you know you want to take like pronoun changes, name changes, HRT, or top surgery, you might include those as your plans.

]]>
    </string>
    <string name="c05">
        <![CDATA[
        Many social media platforms today are moving towards being more inclusive of transgender users. On facebook, you can change your gender at any time to male, female, or a custom option, and select whether or not you want it to be shown on your timeline. Making a general post on social media can be a great way to come out remotely to a lot of people you know without having to individually contact everyone you might want to tell. When you are ready, write a short post about being transgender, deciding to transition, and announce any new names and pronouns - or a TBD! Add a picture of yourself that makes you feel good - featuring a new haircut or favorite clothes. If you would like, many social media accounts offer options to disable comments on particular posts, but you might be surprised by the supportive comments you’ll get! Including pronouns in your bio can help people get used to associating you with your correct ones.

]]>
    </string>
    <string name="c06">
        <![CDATA[
        For many of us, it is helpful to discuss our pronouns or new name with an instructor at the beginning of a course. Once you receive your schedule, write a short email to your instructors introducing yourself, what class of theirs you will be in, and how you want to be addressed. This is especially helpful if you have a name you go by that is not your legal name. Here’s an example template of what you might write:
<h6></h6>
Hello, <br />
   My name is (chosen name) and I will be joining your (class name or code) class this semester. I wanted to reach out ahead of time to let you know that while I am listed in your class as (legal name) I go by (chosen name) and use (pronouns like he/him or they/them) pronouns. I look forward to a good semester with you.
<h6></h6>
Thanks,<br />
    (Chosen name)
<h6></h6>
On the first day of class, try to get there a few minutes early to greet the instructor and introduce yourself in person, reminding them of what your legal name is and what your chosen name and pronouns are. If they take any kind of role-call, they should now use your preferred name.
<h6></h6>
If your teacher refuses to use your chosen name, get in touch with student services and let them know what is going on. You deserve to be addressed properly just like any other student. Teachers constantly accommodate nicknames, asking them to make a note of your correct name is not being difficult!
<h6></h6>
If you are transitioning mid-semester, you can still send an email to your instructor letting them know of the change, and reminding them in person next time you see them in class.
<h6></h6>
People are not perfect - they may accidentally refer to you by the wrong name or pronouns occasionally, but if you see they are making an effort, try to have some patience as they adjust.

]]>
    </string>
    <string name="c07">
        <![CDATA[Coming out in a workplace is best put simply and without as much personal information as you might tell a friend. At any interview, your interviewer will likely ask you to tell them a bit about yourself. Including your chosen name and pronouns in with whatever else you’d like to tell them is a great way to start off. You also might introduce yourself only by your chosen name, and let them know later when it comes to paperwork that your legal name is different from what you go by.
<h6></h6>
Your interviewer might ask you about it. Legally, employers cannot ask you about sexual orientation. If you work a job that involves working with customers or clients, they might ask you how you would respond to a customer misgendering you. You might tell them you don’t see the need to address it with clients, or that you will politely correct them and move on, or however you best would handle the situation. Remember that an interview isn’t just for your employer, it’s for you, too - to get a feel for the duties, climate, and general fit for the job. If your interviewer is rude or nosy about your gender identity or anything else, this might not be a good fit for you. That’s okay! There are tons of jobs out there, listed on boards or online, and more and more employers are working to make jobs safe and supportive of trangender staff.
<h6></h6>
If you already work at a place you would like to come out at, you might start with discussing a new name or pronouns with a manager in a private conversation. Tell them you have a new name and/or pronouns you will be going by. Ask them to help you with changing your name on any ID or schedule your previous name might be listed on. If you have a good manager, you might ask how best you might come out to your coworkers, if there is a time during a staff meeting you could speak briefly about it or a similar situation where they could give you the floor. You could also just mention it to coworkers individually when you have a moment to speak with them. You don’t owe anyone your life story, and a simple statement should suffice. Example: “Actually, I go by Alex and he/him pronouns now.”
<h6></h6>
If you are made to feel uncomfortable or unsafe in your workplace due to being transgender, many companies have a Human Resources (HR) department that can help.

]]>
    </string>
    <string name="c08">
        <![CDATA[When greeting a new person, you might include your pronouns with your name. You could also let them ask, or if they assume and address you incorrectly you can correct them casually.
<h6></h6>
Example: “Oh, actually I go by they/them.”
<h6></h6>
When people are corrected on using your name or pronouns, they can become defensive. When people are told they have done something wrong, no matter how small, it is easier to turn the blame out onto someone else. Using a light and casual tone when you correct someone can help them to feel less defensive.
<h6></h6>
It is important to note, however, that you are not responsible for their reaction or behavior. It is normal to feel frustrated by other people using the wrong name or pronouns. You are responsible for the way you handle it, and they are responsible for how they do in turn.

]]>
    </string>

    <string name="t01">
    <![CDATA[First, remember there is no right or wrong way to transition! Transitioning is about what makes you happy and comfortable. Some ways people can transition can include:
<ul>
<li>Dressing in different clothes</li>
<li>Changing hairstyle</li>
<li>Wearing makeup</li>
<li>Being addressed by different pronouns</li>
<li>Changing your name</li>
<li>Changing your legal gender marker</li>
<li>Undergoing full or partial Hormone Replacement Therapy (HRT)</li>
<li>Getting gender-affirming “top” surgery (breast reduction or augmentation)</li>
<li>Getting gender affirming “bottom” surgery (affecting the genitals such as phalloplasty or vaginoplasty)</li>
<li>Plastic surgery to masculinize or feminize facial/neck features</li>
<li>Voice training</li>
<li>Hair implants</li>
<li>Chest binding</li>
<li>Padding with breast forms or hip forms</li>
<li>Shaving body/facial hair</li>
<li>Packing or tucking</li>
<li>An exercise routine that emphasizes a masculine, feminine, or androgynous body shape</li>
</ul>
These are some ways people might choose to transition, but it isn’t a checklist! For some, HRT and gender affirming top and bottom surgeries are best for them. For others, it might just be HRT. For another, it might just be changing name and pronouns. For someone else, it could be getting a hysterectomy and voice training - do you see what we are getting at here? There is no “right” OR “wrong” way to transition, or an arbitrary amount you have to transition or WANT to transition in order to be trans!
<h6></h6>
How you may want to transition may also be something you’re unsure about, and things you want might change over time. You might not want HRT, but later feel you would really benefit from it - or you might think you want HRT, but after more research on it, decide it’s not what’s best for you. That’s okay! Explore what appeals to you and best represents your true self.
]]>
    </string>

    <string name="d01">
    <![CDATA[Gender dysphoria is distress and anxiety stemming directly from a difference between one’s assigned sex VS gender identity. Gender dysphoria is treated with transitioning, to better align the physical and social self with your gender identity. Gender dysphoria is not a distorted or warped view and is not a mental illness, but a symptom of a mismatch between your assigned gender and gender identity.
]]>
    </string>
    <string name="d02">
    <![CDATA[
x
]]>
    </string>
    <string name="d03">
    <![CDATA[
There are lots of options for managing dysphoria, it’s just a matter of finding what works best for you! Transitioning or presenting in a gender- affirming way can help manage it long term, and there are other things you can do to manage acute distress from gender dysphoria. Some examples include exercise, taking a walk, wearing gender affirming clothing/makeup, wearing baggy clothes that cover you, or distractions. Reading or watching a movie, cleaning and organizing a small area like a desk or drawer, or talking to a friend can be great distractions from negative thoughts and feelings. Things like meditation, prayer, or grounding techniques can help with self reflection and emotional steadying. Explore the app to find recommendations for managing long term and acute distress from dysphoria.

]]>
    </string>
    <string name="d04">
    <![CDATA[
Experiencing dysphoria is different for every person, as personalized as any other aspect of self acceptance and confidence. For most people, dysphoria begins to alleviate in direct correlation with taking the steps you want to transition, and can be greatly or entirely relieved.
]]>
    </string>
    <string name="d05">
    <![CDATA[
Body dysmorphia is a condition that causes you to see a kind of warped perception of yourself different from your actual appearance, and encourages hyperfixation on one or more perceived flaws you see exaggerated on yourself. This can be focused on any number of things, like fat, muscle, body hair, hairline, acne, or skin tone.
<h6></h6>
Gender dysphoria, on the other hand, is psychological distress stemming directly from a difference between one’s assigned sex VS gender identity.
<h6></h6>
While both relate to discomfort surrounding your body and how you are perceived, they have different roots and treatments. Those suffering from body dysmorphia have a distorted perception of themselves, while those with gender dysphoria are not experiencing a psychological distortion.
<h6></h6>
With body dysmorphia, the perceived flaw cannot be fixed even by drastic measures like surgery, because it will always be viewed through a distortion.
<h6></h6>
Gender dysphoria creates anxiety and depression stemming from a fundamental difference in your physical self VS your true gender identity and expression.
<h6></h6>
Gender dysphoria is treated with transitioning, to better reflect oneself. Gender dysphoria is not a distorted or warped view and is not a mental illness, but a symptom of a mismatch between your assigned gender and gender identity.

]]>
    </string>
    <string name="d06">
    <![CDATA[
Many transgender people begin questioning their gender due to feelings of gender dysphoria they experience even before they understand what it is. Because of this, gender dysphoria is often associated as a kind of catalyst for being transgender.
However, many people do not experience gender dysphoria, yet identify as transgender.
<h6></h6>
Every identity and path to understanding it is different. “Transgender” is a descriptor that ties together millions of people who can, in every other way, be completely different from one another, and have different ideas on their identities. If anything could tie all trans people together, it would probably not be gender dysphoria, but gender euphoria. Gender euphoria is the inverse of gender dysphoria - a euphoric feeling one experiences when presenting or being acknowledged in line with one’s true gender.  If gender dysphoria is anxiety from a mismatch of gender identity, gender euphoria is the joy when that identity is properly matched.
<h6></h6>
Some people experience gender dysphoria, and feel gender euphoria when they transition. Others don’t feel gender dysphoria, but do experience gender euphoria.
Others might not experience a particularly strong gender euphoria, but instead feel it as a relief of gender dysphoria.
<h6></h6>
One’s gender identity is a deeply personal thing, and one that can be difficult to explain because it is so inherent in your being. Every person in the world has a slightly different understanding of their gender identity.
<h6></h6>
Some people pick apart the community to decide who can prove themselves to be transgender “the right way” to them. Our community’s differences are a collage that creates a bigger picture of transgender experiences through time and around the globe. Other people might experience their transgender identity a little different than you do, but that doesn’t make them - or you - any “less” trans, or “fake” trans. Your identity is about you - not what anyone else might think of it.

]]>
    </string>
    <string name="ency_gender_basic">

        <![CDATA[
        <b>Gender</b> is an aspect of your identity in terms of being male, female, or not specifically just male or female.
        Most people are raised with the assumption that gender is tied to sex - associating masculinity and being male with being born with a penis and testicles, and female as being born with a vagina and ovaries.
        \n
        \n
<h6>Gender vs sex</h6>
Most people are raised being taught that gender and sexual characteristics are inherently tied together, when in fact, gender and
        sex are very different things.
<h6></h6>
First, let’s debunk some myths about sex. A person’s sex refers to their first (or “primary”) and secondary sexual
        characteristics. Primary sexual characteristics are present at birth - in humans, the usual example given is having a
        testes and penis or ovaries and a vagina. Secondary characteristics usually develop during puberty, like development of
        breast tissue, muscle, voice changes, facial hair, and body hair.
<h6></h6>
A lowered voice, facial and body hair, high muscle mass, XX chromosomes, and high testosterone levels are
        usually associated with being “masculine” and “male”.
<h6></h6>
A higher voice, sparse body hair, soft skin, breast development, XY chromosomes,  menstruation, and
        high estrogen levels are usually associated with being “feminine” and “female”.
<h6></h6>
However, even without including transgender people, hundreds of millions of people are born and develop
        traits differing from what is associated with their assigned sex. Women assigned female at birth
        can have little to no breast tissue, high testosterone levels, XX chromosomes, lower voices,
        thick body hair, facial hair, and high musculature. Men assigned male at birth can have breast
        tissue and lactation abilities, XY chromosomes, high estrogen, low testosterone, little to no
        body hair or facial hair, a higher voice, and low muscle mass.
<h6></h6>
Cis men and women can have any combination of these secondary characteristics, and people are born
        with infinite variations on appearance and function of their genitals. Many people are born
        with primary sexual characteristics that do not fit easily into being defined as a penis, a
        vagina, testes, ovaries, or can have different combinations.
<h6></h6>
With all of these combinations and variations, there is not one singular trait that defines what makes
        a man a “biological” man, or a woman a “biological” woman. Someone can be born with a penis
        whose sexual characteristics are, in every other way, traits of a cis woman. A person can be
        born with XY chromosomes who, in every other way, present traits of a cis man. There are
        infinite variations and combinations of what traits a person can be born with or develop.
        None of these traits, combinations, or acceptions decide what gender you identify as.
<h6></h6>
Next, let’s debunk some ideas about what gender is. In almost any culture, there are ideas about
        what things are considered “feminine” and “masculine” - everything from scents to clothes
        to colors to hairstyles to hobbies to professions. However, none of these things are worldwide
        or static in any way. In America, the color blue is linked with masculinity and the color pink
        with femininity. But these colors don’t have genders, they are just colors. Before WWII,
        the color blue was actually associated with femininity, and the color pink with masculinity.
        Nothing about the colors have changed since then except for their opinion in popular culture and society.

        <h6>Ok</h6> tee if youre reading this im stopping for now to go eat k love you byee]]>
    </string>
</resources>