<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Transverse</string>
    <string name="page_encyclopedia">Encyclopedia</string>
    <string name="page_add_new">Add New Entry</string>
    <string name="page_statistics">Statistics</string>
    <string name="page_self_help">Self-Help</string>
    <string name="page_settings">Settings</string>

    <!-- ADD NEW ENTRY FRAGMENT -->
    <string name="ane_mood_header">How are you feeling?</string>
    <string name="ane_tags_header">Tags</string>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">UwU</string>

    <!--ENCYCLOPEDIA ENTRIES -->
    <string name="ency_gender_basic">
        <![CDATA[<font size="48">What is gender?</font>
        <br />
        <b>Gender</b> is an aspect of your identity in terms of being male, female, or not specifically just male or female.
        Most people are raised with the assumption that gender is tied to sex - associating masculinity and being male with being born with a penis and testicles, and female as being born with a vagina and ovaries.
        \n
        \n
- Gender vs sex
Most people are raised being taught that gender and sexual characteristics are inherently tied together, when in fact, gender and
        sex are very different things.

First, let’s debunk some myths about sex. A person’s sex refers to their first (or “primary”) and secondary sexual
        characteristics. Primary sexual characteristics are present at birth - in humans, the usual example given is having a
        testes and penis or ovaries and a vagina. Secondary characteristics usually develop during puberty, like development of
        breast tissue, muscle, voice changes, facial hair, and body hair.

A lowered voice, facial and body hair, high muscle mass, XX chromosomes, and high testosterone levels are
        usually associated with being “masculine” and “male”.

A higher voice, sparse body hair, soft skin, breast development, XY chromosomes,  menstruation, and
        high estrogen levels are usually associated with being “feminine” and “female”.

However, even without including transgender people, hundreds of millions of people are born and develop
        traits differing from what is associated with their assigned sex. Women assigned female at birth
        can have little to no breast tissue, high testosterone levels, XX chromosomes, lower voices,
        thick body hair, facial hair, and high musculature. Men assigned male at birth can have breast
        tissue and lactation abilities, XY chromosomes, high estrogen, low testosterone, little to no
        body hair or facial hair, a higher voice, and low muscle mass.

Cis men and women can have any combination of these secondary characteristics, and people are born
        with infinite variations on appearance and function of their genitals. Many people are born
        with primary sexual characteristics that do not fit easily into being defined as a penis, a
        vagina, testes, ovaries, or can have different combinations.

With all of these combinations and variations, there is not one singular trait that defines what makes
        a man a “biological” man, or a woman a “biological” woman. Someone can be born with a penis
        whose sexual characteristics are, in every other way, traits of a cis woman. A person can be
        born with XY chromosomes who, in every other way, present traits of a cis man. There are
        infinite variations and combinations of what traits a person can be born with or develop.
        None of these traits, combinations, or acceptions decide what gender you identify as.

Next, let’s debunk some ideas about what gender is. In almost any culture, there are ideas about
        what things are considered “feminine” and “masculine” - everything from scents to clothes
        to colors to hairstyles to hobbies to professions. However, none of these things are worldwide
        or static in any way. In America, the color blue is linked with masculinity and the color pink
        with femininity. But these colors don’t have genders, they are just colors. Before WWII,
        the color blue was actually associated with femininity, and the color pink with masculinity.
        Nothing about the colors have changed since then except for their opinion in popular culture and society.
        \n
        Ok tee if youre reading this im stopping for now to go eat k love you byee]]>
    </string>
</resources>